In the last video, you saw how to
evaluate an LLM output
in an example where
it had the right answer.
And so we could
write down a function
to explicitly just tell
us if the LLM
outputs the right categories
and list of products.
But what if the LLM is
used to generate text and there isn't
just one right piece of text? Let's take
a look at an approach
for how to evaluate that
type of LLM output.
Here's my usual helper functions, and
given a customer message, "tell
me about the smartx pro
phone and the fotosnap camera.", and
so on. Here are a few utils to
get me the assistant answer. This
is basically the process
that Isa has stepped
through in earlier videos.
And so here's the assistant answer, "Sure,
I'd be happy to help!". Smartphone, the
smartx pro phone, and so
on and so forth.
So, how can you evaluate if this
is a good answer or not?
Seems like there are
lots of possible good answers.
One way to evaluate this
is to write a rubric,
meaning a set of guidelines,
to evaluate this
answer on different dimensions,
and then use that to
decide whether or not you're
satisfied with this answer. Let
me show you how to do that.
So, let me create a
little data structure to
store the customer message
as well as the product info.
So here, I'm going to specify a
prompt for evaluating the
assistant answer using what's called
a rubric. I'll explain in
a second what that means.
But this prompt says
in the system message, "You are an
assistant that evaluates
how well the customer service agent
answers a user question by looking
at the context that the customer
service agent is using to generate
its response.".
So, this response is what we
had further up in the notebook,
that was the assistant answer.
And we're going to specify the
data in this prompt, what
was the customer message, what
was the context, that is, what
was the product and category information
that was provided, and
then what was the output of the LLM.
And then, this is a rubric. So,
we want the LLM to,
"Compare the factual content of the
submitted answer with the context.
Ignore differences in style,
grammar, or punctuation.
And then,
we wanted to check a few things,
like, "Is the assistant
response based only on the context
provided? Does the answer include
information that is not
provided in the context?
Is there any
disagreement between the
response and the context?"
So, this is called a rubric,
and this specifies what
we think the answer
should get right for
us to consider it a good answer.
Then, finally,
we wanted to print out yes or no,
and so on.
And now,
if we were to run this evaluation.
This is what you get.
So it says, "the assistant response
is based only on the context
provided.". It does not, in this case,
seem to make up new information.
There isn't disagreements. User
asked two questions. Answered
question one and
answered question two. So
answered both questions.
So we would look at this output and
maybe conclude that this
is a pretty good response.
And one note, here I'm
using the ChatGPT 3.5 Turbo
model for this evaluation.
For a more robust evaluation,
it might be worth considering using
GPT-4 because even if you deploy 3.5 Turbo
in production and generate a
lot of text, if your
evaluation is a more
sporadic exercise, then it
may be prudent to pay for the somewhat
more expensive GPT-4 API call
to get a more rigorous evaluation
of the output.
One design pattern that I
hope you can take away
from this is that when
you can specify a rubric,
meaning a list of
criteria by which to
evaluate an LLM output,
then you can actually
use another API call
to evaluate your first LLM output.
There's one other design pattern
that could be useful
for some applications, which
is if you can
specify an ideal response. So
here, I'm going to specify a test
example where the customer
message is, "tell me
about the smartx pro phone", and so
on.
And here's an ideal answer. So
this is if you have an expert human
customer service representative write
a really good answer. The
expert says, this
would be a great answer., "Of
course! The SmartX ProPhone is a.".
It goes on to give
a lot of helpful information.
Now, it is unreasonable
to expect any LLM to generate
this exact answer word for word.
And in classical
natural language processing
techniques, there are some
traditional metrics for
measuring if the LLM output is
similar to this
expert human written outputs.
For example, there's
something called the BLEU score, BLEU,
that you can search online
to read more about. They
can measure how similar
one piece of text
is from another. But
it turns out there's an
even better way, which is
you can use a prompt, which I'm
going to specify here, to ask an
LLM to compare how well the
automatically generated customer
service agent output
corresponds to the
ideal expert response
that was written
by a human that I just
showed up above.
Here's the prompt we can use, which
is. We're going to use an LLM
and tell it to be an assistant that
evaluates how well the
customer service agent answers
a user question by
comparing the response, that was
the automatically generated
one, to the
ideal (expert) human written
response.
So we're going to give it the data, which
is what was the customer request, what
is the expert written ideal response,
and then what did our
LLM actually output.
And this rubric comes from the
OpenAI open source evals framework,
which is a fantastic framework with
many evaluation methods
contributed both by
OpenAI developers and
by the broader
open source community.
In fact, if you want
you could contribute an eval to
that framework yourself
to help others evaluate their Large
Language Model outputs.
So in this rubric,
we tell the LLM to,
"Compare the factual content
of the submitted answer
with the expert answer.
Ignore any differences in style,
grammar, or punctuation.".
And feel free to
pause the video and
read through this in detail,
but the key is we ask it to
carry the comparison and
output a score from A to E,
depending on whether the
"submitted answer is a
subset of the expert
answer and is fully consistent",
versus the "submitted answer is
a superset of the expert answer
and is fully consistent with it".
This might mean it hallucinated or
made up some additional facts.
"Submitted answer contains
all the details as the expert
answer.", whether there's
disagreement or whether "the
answers differ, but
these differences don't matter
from the perspective of factuality".
And the LLM will pick whichever
of these seems to be the
most appropriate description.
So here's the assistant answer that
we had just now. I think it's a
pretty good answer, but now let's see what
the things when it compares
the assistant answer to test
set ID. Oh, looks like it
got an A.
And so it thinks
"The submitted answer is
a subset of the
expert answer and is
fully consistent with it",
and that sounds right to me.
This assistant answer is
much shorter than the
long expert answer up top,
but it does hopefully is consistent.
Once again, I'm using GPT-3.5 Turbo in
this example, but to get
a more rigorous evaluation, it might make
sense to use GPT-4 in your own
application.
Now, let's
try something totally different. I'm
going to have a very
different assistant answer, "life is
like a box of chocolates", quote from
a movie called "Forrest Gump".
And if we were to evaluate that it
outputs D and it concludes that,
"there is a disagreement
between the submitted answer",
life is like a box
of chocolate and the expert answer.
So it correctly assesses this to
be a pretty terrible answer.
And so that's it. I
hope you take away from
this video two design patterns.
First is, even without an
expert provided ideal answer,
if you can write a rubric,
you can use one
LLM to evaluate another LLM's
output.
And second, if you can provide
an expert provided ideal answer,
then that can help
your LLM better compare if, and if a
specific assistant output
is similar to the expert provided
ideal answer. I hope that helps you
to evaluate your LLM systems
outputs.
So that both during development
as well as when the
system is running and you're
getting responses, you
can continue to monitor its performance
and also have
these tools to
continuously evaluate and
keep on improving
the performance of
your system.